Marcio Moreira Junior

System Administrator | IT Infrastructure Specialist | DevOps Engineer | SRE | Cloud Engineer

Address: Rua Rodrigues Alves, 119 - ZIP 18080-693 - Sorocaba/SP/Brazil

Phone: +55 15 99885-4030 / +55 15 99732-6744

E-mail: mdmjunior@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced DevOps Engineer with over 24 years in IT, I started as a Linux Systems Administrator and worked as one till the world changed into this automated stuff. I focused on specializing in Network Infrastructure, Cybersecurity, and operating systems. I am 42 years old and have been deeply involved with Linux and FreeBSD since 1998, which sparked my passion for technology. Since 2000, I have worked consistently in the IT industry, gaining extensive experience in implementing, maintaining, and supporting complex networks and data systems. My career has been focused on ensuring high reliability and productivity in IT environments, with a strong emphasis on automation, containerization, cloud computing, and security. My last professional experiences were in Telecom companies, which provided me with knowledge about telecommunication networks which allowed me to work in other areas. I am proficient in several technologies including Ansible (for Linux and MacOS), Terraform, LXD containers, NAS, Docker, Kubernetes, and GCP, among others, and have successfully contributed to several teams in Brazilian and international companies.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Operating Systems: Linux (All flavors), FreeBSD, OpenBSD, Solaris, AIX, Windows, Mac OS;

Networking: TCP/IP, LAN, WAN, DNS, SDN, IPv6, Cisco Routers, Fortinet;

Development: Bash Script, Python Scripting, GoLang;

Automation: Ansible, Terraform, Puppet, Chef, Rundeck, OpenStack;

Virtualization: QEMU, VMWare, VirtualBox, ProxMox;

Containers: LXD, Docker, ProxMox; **CI/CD:** Gitlab, Github Actions, Jenkins;

Observability: Grafana, FluentD, Prometheus, Nagios, Zabbix, New Relic, ElasticSearch, Logstash, Datadog;

Databases: MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL;

Orchestration: Kubernetes, Swarm;

Storage: Ceph, GlusterFS, NFS, Veritas Infoscale;

Security: OpnSense, KeyCloak, FortiGate Appliances, OpenVPN; Crowdstrike Falcon; **Cloud Computing:** AWS, GCP, Azure, Digital Ocean, Linode, Vultr, Oracle Cloud;

Application Management: Gorilla and Munki (for MacOS)

EXPERIENCE

Mobi2Buy – Rio de Janeiro/Brazil (October 2024)

DevOps Engineer

Responsible for managing Linux and OpenBSD servers, deploying applications using Docker and Swarm, and maintaining cloud infrastructure on AWS and Azure. Implements CI/CD pipelines via GitHub Actions and automates server provisioning with VMware vCenter. Oversees Kubernetes and Docker Swarm clusters for container orchestration.

- Server's Management (Linux Debian, Ubuntu, OpenBSD);
- Application Deployment (Docker, docker swarm);
- CI/CD (Github Actions);
- Server Deployment (VMWare VCenter);

- Cloud Administration (AWS, Azure);
- Container orchestration (Kubernetes, Docker Swarm);

WiLine Networks – San Francisco/USA (July 2022 to July 2024)

Senior SysOps Engineer

Managed infrastructure automation with Terraform, Ansible, and AWX, provisioning LXD host nodes and CI/CD pipelines in Gitlab. Developed Bash scripts to streamline workflows and Rundeck jobs for automation. Administered multi-cloud environments (AWS, GCP, Vultr) and storage solutions (GlusterFS, Ceph, ProxMox). Ensured Observability with Prometheus, Grafana, and Zabbix while supporting Development, Networking, and Security teams.

- Server's Infrastructure Management (Netbox, Prometheus, Grafana, Zabbix, Jira, Confluence);
- Deployment of Servers Host nodes for LXD Containers (Terraform);
- Python programming to automate tasks (Bash, Rundeck);
- Develop, maintain and update Ansible playbooks (Ansible, AWX);
- CI/CD pipelines creation (Gitlab);
- Support for Development, Networking and Security teams;
- Cloud Computing administration (Vultr, GCP, AWS);
- Storage administration (GlusterFS, Ceph, ProxMox);
- Backup administration (zfs-autobackup, Rundeck, BackupPC);
- Container orchestration (Kubernetes, Docker Swarm, ProxMox);

Oi SA – São Paulo/Brazil (June 2020 to June 2022)

Senior System Administrator

Administered Linux (Debian, Ubuntu, Red Hat, CentOS) and Unix (Solaris, AIX) environments, automated provisioning with Terraform, and maintained Ansible playbooks and Puppet models for infrastructure as code. Managed FreeIPA for LDAP authentication, optimized cloud operations in AWS and GCP, and handled storage with Veritas Infoscale. Deployed and monitored containerized applications using Docker Swarm.

- Server's Administration (Linux Debian, Ubuntu, Red Hat, CentOS, Solaris, AIX, VMWare VCenter);
- Develop, maintain and update Ansible playbooks (Ansible, AWX);
- Cloud Computing administration (AWS, GCP);
- LDAP Administration (FreeIPA);
- Operating system troubleshooting;
- Server's provisioning (Terraform);
- Container orchestration (Docker Swarm);
- Storage Administration (Veritas Infoscale);

Computouch INC - Tulsa - Oklahoma/USA (December 2014 to March 2020)

Senior Infrastructure Analyst

Designed and implemented network architectures while managing Windows and Linux servers. Maintained backup solutions with BackupPC and optimized storage management using TrueNAS. Led security design and management, ensuring infrastructure resilience and data integrity.

- Network Design;
- Servers administration and provisioning (Windows Server, Linux Red Hat);
- Backup Management (BackupPC);
- Storage Management (TrueNAS);
- Security Design and Management;

OpenUX Serviços e Soluções em TI – Blumenau/Brazil (October 2013 to October 2014) Senior Infrastructure Consultant

Provided consulting services in network architecture, server administration, and database management. Configured and managed Fortinet appliances for security enforcement. Delivered customer support for IT infrastructure while maintaining storage solutions.

- Network Architeture
- Server's Administration
- Fortinet Appliances configuration and management
- Customer Support for infrastructure
- Database Management
- Storage Management

Previous experience upon request.

EDUCATION | COURSES | IDIOMS

- Graduated in Computer Networks Faculdade IBTA Sorocaba/SP
- Masters in Applied Computing Univali Itajai/SC
- · Advanced in English, intermediate Spanish, basic Italian (Work in development);
- Cisco Certified Network Associate CCNA Impacta/São Paulo SP
- Red Hat Fast Track for RHCE Red Hat/São Paulo SP